[The Heir]
[Episode 33]
[City Gate of She County,
Huizhou Prefecture]
With way too many refugees right now,
it might lead to turmoil.
Hurry to ask Lord He for instructions
on how to handle this.
Yes.
Mother, Zhengliang.
How was it going?
Thankfully, Zhengliang ran fast
and got to the front of the line.
The price at the rice shop
has increased by 40% to 50%
within half an hour.
This is never going to end, is it?
How are the common people
supposed to survive?
Magistrate He
has already sent officers
to the ink workshop to inform us.
The miners' riot this time
has affected Ningguo and Huizhou.
Also, the Japanese pirates along the river
are using this to pillage everywhere.
The trade routes
in and out of Huizhou are also cut off.
Magistrate He
has called on the merchants of Huizhou
to work with the prefectural office,
giving away porridge to help the needy,
pacifying the refugees,
and getting through this crisis together.
How are things going at the ink workshop?
Don't worry.
For the orders the ink workshop
took previously,
I have prepared sufficient materials.
The delivery of the ink products
won't be a problem.
I heard this time, Marshal Qi will
deploy troops to suppress the rebellion.
It probably won't last for long.
And this gave me
the chance to be back
and spend some time with Mother
and Grandfather.
And I can also talk more
with my unborn nephew.
During this time,
I'll keep watch at night.
Mother, you should also go out less.
If you need to go out,
you must call me to go with you.
Zhen,
how are things going at the main house?
Eldest Aunt has also sent people
to buy food and rice.
Excluding the portion
for porridge distribution,
if they live frugally,
surviving for half a year
won't be a problem.
So don't worry.
Benchang!
Young Master Wu's letter arrived.
Keep it down!
Benchang,
I have found a way
for the matter we discussed before.
Just wait for the good news.
Also, regarding your previous question,
I've sent someone to check
with the Ministry of Revenue.
Qi Jiu's original name
was Wang Fuquan.
He's from the north.
His family has all passed away.
In the 39th year of Jiajing's Reign,
he joined Marshal Qi's army.
There is nothing suspicious.
Best regards, Wu Weishi.
The north?
The 39th year of Jiajing's Reign?
Isn't that...
Bensheng.
Do you remember which year
we moved into this mansion?
Three years ago, when the Luo family fell,
Luo Wensong tried to run away
but failed and died.
Their second young master
managed to escape,
but it was said he also died in the north.
So we moved in.
Go to the posthouse later
and send this letter to Nanjing.
After sending the letter,
go to the prefectural office
and find Officer Zhang,
who is on good terms with us.
What for?
Ask him to pull out the arrest warrants
issued for Luo Wenqian
from the 39th year of Jiajing's Reign.
Understood.
We invited
all the ink workshop managers here today.
I guess
you all know the reason.
Recently,
the miners have been rioting.
Our raw materials can't be transported in,
and the ink
can't be shipped out.
The Huizhou ink industry
is facing another crisis.